A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Humanities and the Arts, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Wilson McNeil Lowry FA582
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Speeches and Writings, 1955-1974; V
  - Studio Arena Theatre Conference, Wilson McNeil Lowry speech, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Studio Arena Theatre Conference, Wilson McNeil Lowry speech - Reel III, 1967; 1/4 inch audio tape; Sound, 12 minutes (Box 28, Reel AV 6314)
      Conclusion of conference speech given by Wilson McNeil Lowry.
  - "Handicaps to the Press's Contribution to Increasing Communication Among Peoples," UNESCO 5th National Conference, Cincinnati, OH, 1955 November 3-5 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - "The Humanities and the Private Colleges," Meeting of the Federation of Illinois Colleges, Blackburn College, Carlinville, IL, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - "Higher Education and the Individual," Louisiana College Conference, Alexandria, LA, 1957 March 1 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - "Institutional Cooperation in Higher Education," Midwest Conference on Graduate Study and Research, Chicago, IL, 1957 April 1 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - "Role of the Foundation in American Society," The Nassau Club, Princeton, NJ, 1958 April 16 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - "Economics of the Arts in America," Voice of America Forum Lectures (published lecture), 1960 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - "Patronage of the Arts: The United States," Congress for Cultural Freedom, West Berlin, Germany, 1960 June 21 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - "Music and the Ford Foundation," Music Journal (published article), 1961 April (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Talk on FF Program in Humanities and the Arts, American Federation of Arts Convention, Chicago, IL, 1961 April 14 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - "Ford Foundation and the Theatre," Equity Magazine (published article), 1961 May (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Remarks at the Dedication of the New Arena Stage, Washington, D.C., 1961 October 9 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - "Ford Foundation Program in Contemporary Opera," Opera News (published article), 1961 December 6 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - "The Ford Foundation and the Creative Arts," Los Angeles, CA, 1962 January 10 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - "The University and the Creative Arts," Educational Theatre Journal (published article, reprinted by FF), 1962 May (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - "The Role of the Arts and the Humanities" by Lowry and Gertrude S. Hooker, American Assembly Report on International Educational and Cultural Exchange, 1962 August 24 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Remarks at the Dedication of the Ohio University Fine Arts Building, Athens, OH, 1962 November 9 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - "The Ford Foundation and the Creative Arts," North Carolina State Art Society Meeting, Raleigh, NC, 1962 December 5 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - "The Arts and Philanthropy," Poses Lecture Series, Brandeis University, Waltham, MA, 1962 December 10 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - "How Are the Arts Best Supported?" Pomona College Symposium, Claremont, CA, 1963 February 21 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - "The Commitment to Culture and the Arts," 46th Annual Meeting of the American Council on Education, Washington, D.C., reprinted in The Educational Record, Winter 1964 (published article), 1963 October 2-4 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - "The Foundation and the Arts," Manhattan School of Music Symposium, New York, NY, 1963 November 11 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - "The Arts in Today's Society," MENC Biennial Meeting, Philadelphia, PA, reprinted in Music Educators Journal (published article), 1964 March 13-17 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Remarks at Commencement, Juilliard School, New York, NY, 1964 May 29 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - "The Contemporary University: The Arts," Daedalus (submission for publication), 1965 March (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - "The Resident Professional Theatre," Transcript of Background Interview for NET, 1965 July 1 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - "Art and Intensity," The Martha Graham Convocation, Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, Aspen, CO (reprinted by the FF), 1965 July 30 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - "Opportunities for Philanthropy in the Arts," Conference of Southwest Foundations, Houston, TX, 1967 April 14 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - "The University and the Creative Arts: II," First Annual Fine Arts Festival, Edwardsville, IL, 1967 April 16 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Studio Arena Theatre Conference Tape Transcription, Buffalo Theatre Conference, Buffalo, NY, 1967 April 21 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - "National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities: Part I - National Endowment for the Humanities," Statement, Joint Open Hearing of the Senate Special Subcommittee on Arts and Humanities and the House Special Subcommittee on Labor, Washington, D.C., 1967 July 12 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - "Community Objectives in the Arts," (Transcript, Verbatim), The Arts in Missouri Conference, Columbia, MO, 1967 October 2 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - "The Arts in Education," Bank Street College of Education at New FF Headquarters Building, New York, NY, 1967 December 9 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Commencement Address, Minneapolis School of Art, Minneapolis, MN, 1968 May 3 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Houston Chronicle Article on Nina Vance (submission for publication), 1968 October (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - "The Economic Crisis in the Arts: The Need for a National Policy," from the Ford Foundation 1968 Annual Report, 1968 November (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - "The Milieu Crisis in the Arts," Delos Symposium, 1969 Athens Ekistics Month, Athens, Greece, 1969 July 15 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - "The Role of Foundations in the Arts and Humanities," draft (unpublished) Written for Encyclopedia of Education, 1969 August (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - "This Moment in the Arts," New Alley Theatre Dedication, Houston, Texas, Reprinted in Forum Magazine (published article, reprinted by FF), 1969 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - "National Endowment for the Humanities," Statement to House Committee on Education and Labor, February 4, 1970, 1970 February 4 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Transcript of Testimony Before House Select Subcommittee on Education (unedited draft), 1970 February 4 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Presentation of Association of American Dance Companies Award to Roger L. Stevens, 1970 June 5 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Century Club Board of Management Retirement Speech, 1970 December 16 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - "Comparisons with a Large Foundation," Chapter from The University as an Organization, Carnegie Commission (published article), 1971 June (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Excerpts from Testimony at Hearings of the Select Subcommittee on Education on the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities, 1973 March 20 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Speech to Central Opera Service, New York Sheraton Hotel, New York, NY, 1973 October 15 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Comments on FF programs in music, Chairmen/Presidents Meeting of Association of Independent Colleges of Music, Juilliard School, New York, NY, 1973 October 30 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - "On Bearing Witness," (role of arts and humanities) Association of College, University and Community Arts Administrators, New York, NY, 1973 December 16 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Speech on Role of Arts to the Maryland Institute, Baltimore, MD, 1974 April 28 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - "The Arts and the Society," Jo Tyler Lecture, University of Missouri at Kansas City, Kansas City, MO, 1974 May 7 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - "Notes on the Economics of Music," Duke University, Durham, NC, 1974 October 18 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Notes for Arden House Talk on Museums, American Assembly, Harriman, NY, 1974 November 1 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Ylvisaker, Paul N., Address, Comments on Urbanization, 1963 Citizen's Conference on Community Planning, Indianapolis, IN, 1963 January 11 (Box 27, Folder 28)